Let’s get started with accessing directories using the command prompt.
To locate the ccache compiler using whereis:
1. At the command prompt, type whereis ccache
2. Press ENTER.
To display the present working directory:
1. Type pwd and press ENTER.
To change to the /usr/bin directory:
1. At the command prompt, type cd /usr/bin and press ENTER.
To change to your home directory:
1. At the command prompt, type cd ~ or cd.
2. Press ENTER.
To change to the parent directory of your current directory:
1. At the command prompt, type cd ..
2. Press ENTER.
To change to the previous directory:
1. At the command prompt, type cd -.
2. Press ENTER.
To check where you are with pwd:
2. Type pwd and press ENTER.