Let&#39;s see how to locate the Firefox application in &quot;Locate Firefox&quot;.
Click &quot;Activities&quot; on the top left corner of your desktop.
On the left panel, click the &quot;Show applications&quot; icon.
Click the Firefox icon.
Close Firefox by clicking &quot;Close&quot; in the top right corner of the Firefox window.
Next, let&#39;s explore the Home directory using the File Manager: try to view files in list mode, create a new empty document, save it, and remove it.
Click &quot;Activities&quot; in the upper left corner of your desktop.
In the left panel, click the File Manager icon.
This will by default open the Home directory.
To view files in list mode, click the List icon in the upper right of the File Manager window.
Double-click the Document directory to open it.
Click Activities in the top left corner of your desktop to launch gedit.
Type gedit in the Search box.
Click the gedit icon to open it.
Type your name and click Close in the top right corner of the gedit window to create and close a file.
Click Save As to save the created file.
Select Documents from the left panel of the Save As window.
Type Test to save the file by that name.
Click Save to save the file and close gedit.
This brings you back to the Document directory.
Right-click the Test file in the Document window.
Select Move to Trash to remove the file.