Recent Enterprise Linux distributions all are rather similar in how they start up and shut down.
This is because they&#39;re using rather similar versions of the GNOME desktop, and also, they&#39;re using systemd for initialization services.
So, in order to demonstrate that, on a Red Hat 7 host system, we will run three virtualized Enterprise Linux distributions using VMware Player.
So, let me just get that set up. I&#39;ll start up the 3 instances.
And in the first one I&#39;ll set it up to run Ubuntu 18.04, and the second one I&#39;ll set it up to run CentOS 7. The third one I&#39;ll set up to run openSUSE.
Now, there&#39;ll be some warning messages as we go about not having proper graphics drivers for the virtualized instances,
and as I start up the second and third machine there&#39;ll be some warnings about running more than one virtual machine at once.
But we can safely ignore these warnings.
So, first, I&#39;ll start up the Ubuntu 18.04.
Second, I will initialize the CentOS 7,
and third, I will start up the openSUSE virtual machine.
And there are those warnings about running more than one...
I&#39;ll have somewhat different initial screens, but then, once they enter the startup phase, they&#39;re all pretty similar.
Generally, finally Ubuntu probably starts a little bit faster, then CentOS - the second fastest, and the openSUSE it tends to take a little bit longer.
So here on the Ubuntu - let me type in the password now. And I&#39;ll wait a little bit on the CentOS one because I want to show you that CentOS and openSUSE look absolutely the same.
So, while SUSE is still initializing, I&#39;ll type in the password for CentOS, and you&#39;ll notice the openSUSE screen looks absolutely the same for what&#39;s called the greeter, the only difference being the logo.
So, I sign both those in,
and for both the CentOS and openSUSE we have put in a customized background.
We just picked a picture. For the Ubuntu, we haven&#39;t done anything, so that&#39;s the standard background screen that comes by default during the installation.
To shut it down, I go to the upper right corner, I click on the power button, I click on the power icon, and then I could choose to restart, but I&#39;ll just say &quot;Power off&quot;.
For the CentOS 7 it&#39;s the same procedure. You&#39;ll see that... I&#39;ll just shut it down. And then I&#39;ll do the same thing for the openSUSE machine.
Once again, it looks absolutely the same. It&#39;ll shut off quite cleanly.
So you can see that, for recent distributions, things are pretty similar and you don&#39;t have to worry about how different things would be depending on which distribution you&#39;re using.