We are now going to demonstrate basic software package management on a CentOS 7 system using a graphical interface.
The easiest way to do this is to go through the Applications menu in the upper left corner.
Scroll down to System Tools, and then go over to Software.
And this lists the different kinds of software that&#39;s on the system, organized by category.
It&#39;s a pretty minimal interface, but quite useful.
So, for instance, on desktops, you see, I could have GNOME, KDE, Xfce, etc.
There are different possibilities.
And these are the packages that are associated with these different desktops.
If I want to search for a particular kind of package, let&#39;s say I&#39;ll look at gnuplot, g-n-u-p-l-o-t
it&#39;s searching the database on the system, and it found here, with the check marks, I have already installed gnuplot and gnuplot-common.
Suppose I want to install the documentation package, which is a simple but small package...
So here, gnuplot-doc, so I clicked on that, I said Apply Changes...
it&#39;s asking me for the root password because I&#39;m installing software, and then it did that very quickly... it&#39;s a very small package.
And if I want to remove it, then I can just uncheck the box here now, and click Apply Changes,
and it&#39;s going to ask me to okay that is what I really wanted to do...
If you&#39;re required any other software packages to be removed at the same time, it would let me know about that now,
just as when I installed it, if it required other software packages to be installed to enable this to run, it would have told me that too.
So I just say Continue. Once again, it&#39;s asking me for the super user password, and it&#39;s done.
So that&#39;s all you have to do to easily install or remove just a single package on the system from a graphical interface.