Let&#39;s demonstrate some basic package management functions on an openSUSE system using the zipper utility.
So first, let&#39;s look for all packages with &quot;zypper search&quot; that have the string gnuplot in them.
And we see a number of packages. Let&#39;s concentrate on the documentation package [gnuplot-doc].
So, suppose I try to install that and for that, I have to be a super user for an installation.
So, I do &quot;sudo zypper install gnuplot-doc&quot;.
And you notice it&#39;s telling me and I will not only have to install gnuplot-doc, I would have to install gnuplot, which is the actual program that gnuplot-doc documents.
So, I&#39;ll say sure, yes.
And it&#39;s being done successfully. If I want to get some information about the package, I can do &quot;rpm -qi gnuplot-doc&quot;, and for this, once again, I do not have to be root.
And it&#39;s telling me the name, the version, the size, all sorts of things. And, under the purpose, it&#39;s telling me it includes the man and the info pages for this rather useful plotting program.
Now, suppose I want to remove this package. I can do &quot;zypper remove gnuplot&quot;. Let&#39;s say I try to remove gnuplot, not gnuplot-doc,
and it&#39;s telling me that, if I remove gnuplot, I also have to remove gnuplot-doc, because otherwise there would be unmet dependencies.
So, I say yes, for sure, and now both of them are gone.
So that&#39;s the basic steps you would take to look for a package, install it, get some information about it, and remove it using zypper.