So, let's do some basic package management on an Ubuntu system using Debian packaging.
We're going to use the high-level utilities which understand dependencies: apt-cache and apt-get.
So, first, let's look for all packages that contain the string wget2. So we do that with apt-cache search wget2, and it comes up with wget2 and wget2-dev.
This is an enhancement to the standard wget utility, which is used for recursive downloading of the content of a website or some other kinds of resources.
So, let's just try an install. So, do sudo apt-get install wget2-dev.
And it's telling me it also needs to install libwget0 and wget2.
It shouldn't be that surprising that you need to install the base packages on which the development packages build on.
And it will download 264 kB of archives, but once everything is installed, it will expand out to 805 kB.
So, let's just say yes. I'll type y. And it quickly goes ahead and does all that.
Now, suppose we want to remove wget2-dev. Or, more interesting, let's try to remove wget itself.
So, what is it doing? Oh, I shouldn't have removed wget. I meant wget2. wget I do not want to remove. So, I'll type it again with the 2.
And you see, it wants to remove wget2-dev as well, because without wget2, wget2-dev doesn't have much meaning.
Ok and we no longer need the libwget0. It's sort of orphaned out, but we'll leave it there for now.
So, I'll just say yes and I have removed things from my system.
So, that's the most basic operations you would need to do on an Ubuntu system using Debian packaging.