Let&#39;s gain some experience using the info command for documentation.
So, suppose I type &quot;info make&quot;, I will get information about the make utility used by all programmers,
and this takes me to the top of the info page or the head node.
If I want to look for a particular topic, I can hit /, and you&#39;ll see at the bottom it&#39;s prompting me for search. So, I&#39;ll say example, and it brought me down here to Rule  Example.
If I just hit return, I get that page. Now, at the top, you&#39;ll notice it says the node is Rule Example, the next one is Rule Syntax. So, if I hit an N, I get the Rule Syntax. It says the next one is Prerequisite Types, so if I hit N again, I get Prerequisite Types.
If I hit P, I will go back to the previous one. So, I hit P - Rule Syntax.
If I want to look again for example, I can just hit the / again, and it&#39;s prompting me for the same string. So, I&#39;ll just hit return.
And I&#39;m finding a later example about Wildcard Examples. And if I hit return, I find out above that. If I want to go all the way up, I can hit it a U. it takes me to the top of section 4.4.
I hit U again, I&#39;m at chapter four. I hit U again, I&#39;m at the very top of everything.
If I want to get information on the various keystroke bindings, I can hit an H for help, and you&#39;ll see in the bottom window, where the focus is shifted to, it lists all the possible keystrokes and what they can do.
So, that&#39;s basically how I would use info. I hit Q, I am out of it. And the rest you can learn by navigating within the info page of any topic that interests you.