To log on to the system, perform the following steps:
1. Click on the desired user. In this case it is test2.
The Password box is displayed.
2. Enter the password for user test2.
3. Click Sign In.
The Desktop is displayed.
Note that the session will load the default or the previous session's choice of desktop environment.
After entering your username and password, it could take a little while for the graphical environment to start up, depending on your personal settings.
To log off of the system, perform the following steps:
1. On the openSUSE screen, click the power icon in the top-right corner.
2. Click test2.
3. Click Log Out.
Click Log Out in the confirmation box.