Let's get started with how to navigate through the directory history using the command prompt.
1. Let us say, we have two directories named dir1 and dir2 created under tmp directory and the current working directory is the test3's home directory.
2. To change from test3's home directory to dir1 under tmp directory, at the command prompt type cd /tmp/dir1 and press Enter.
3. To push the current directory to stack type pushd. and press Enter.
Now you working directory is dir1.
4. Now To change to dir2 under tmp directory, at the command prompt type cd /tmp/dir2 and press Enter.
Now you working directory is dir2.
5. To push the current directory to stack, type pushd. and press Enter.
Now, the stack contains the details of the last two directories that you have pushed.
6. To view the directories in the stack, at the command prompt type dirs and press Enter.
You can see the names of the two directories you have pushed to the stack
7. To pop the top-most directory from the stack, at the command prompt type popd and press Enter.
8. To check the current working directory, at the command prompt type pwd and press Enter.
9. To pop the top-most directory from the stack, at the command prompt type popd and press Enter.
10. To check the current working directory, at the command prompt type pwd and press Enter.
Now you're working directory is changed to dir1
11. To pop the top-most directory from the stack, at the command prompt type popd and press Enter.
Since, no entries are available in the stack you get a notification