Let's get started with using the ps command.
To use the ps command with various qualifiers:
1. Open the command prompt.
2. To view all the processes in the current shell, type ps and press Enter.
All the current processes, along with their attributes, are displayed.
3. To view all the processes in the system in full format, type ps -ef and press Enter.
4. To view the current processes along with the list of threads, type ps -eLf and press Enter.
All the current processes and threads, along with their attributes, are displayed.
5. To view all processes for all users using the BSD style, type ps aux and press Enter.
All the processes for all users, along with their attributes, are displayed.
6. To view the current processes with full information in a specific format, type ps axo stat,priority,pid,pcpu,comm and press Enter.
All the current processes, along with the specified attributes, are displayed.