Let's get started on how to use the different wildcards to search for files.
To view all files in the current directory using the ls command:
1. At the command prompt, type ls –a command and press ENTER.
2. All the files under current directory are displayed
To search for files using the Bash wildcard:
1. At the command prompt, type the ls ba?.? command.
2. Press ENTER.
All the filenames starting with "ba", plus a single character,
plus a single character extension are shown.
To search for files using the * Bash wildcard:
1. At the command prompt, type the ls *.out command.
2. Press ENTER.
All the filenames having the .out extension are displayed.
To search for files using the set Bash wildcard notation:
1. At the command prompt, type the ls ba[a-s].c command.
2. Press ENTER.
All the filenames starting with "ba" and have an alphabetic character between a and s are displayed.
To search for files using the !set Bash wildcard notation:
1. At the command prompt, type the ls ba[!a-s].c command.
2. Press ENTER.
All the filenames starting with "ba" and not having an alphabetic character between a and s are displayed.