Let's get started on viewing files using the different available commands.
To view the entire messages file on screen:
1. At the command prompt, type cat messages.
2. Press ENTER.
To view the entire messages file with scroll-back:
1. At the command prompt, type less messages.
2. Press ENTER.
To view last ten lines of the messages file:
1. At the command prompt, type tail messages.
2. Press ENTER.
To view first ten lines of the messages file:
1. At the command prompt, type head messages.
2. Press ENTER.
To view last three lines of the messages file:
1. At the command prompt, type tail -3 messages.
2. Press ENTER.
To view first three lines of the messages file:
1. At the command prompt, type head -3 messages.
2. Press ENTER.