Let’s get started on working with files and directories using command prompt
To create two empty files test1 & test2 with timestamp : 14 march 2018 2:00 PM:
1. At the command prompt, type touch -t 1803141400 test1 test2.
2. Press ENTER.
To check if files are created:
1. At the command prompt, type ls -l.
2. Press ENTER.
To rename the file test1 to new_test1:
1. At the command prompt, type mv test1 new_test1.
2. Press ENTER.
To remove test2 interactively:
1. At the command prompt, type rm -i test2.
2. Press ENTER.
The Confirmation message is displayed.
3. Type y and press ENTER.
To remove new_test1 forcefully:
1. At the command prompt, type rm -f new_test1.
2. Press ENTER.
To create a directory dir1:
1. At the command prompt, type mkdir dir1.
2. Press ENTER.
To remove a directory dir1: mdir dir1.